http://www.geosociety.org/GSA/Privacy_Policy/GSA/privacy.aspx?hkey=bfa08b30-f008-4ac8-8264-21f02dbe75a8

Skip to main content
Loading
Home
»
Privacy Policy
Geological Society of America
Privacy Policy
www.geosociety.org (the “Site”) is operated by The Geological Society of America, Inc. (“GSA,” “we,” “us,” or “our”).
This Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) describes generally how GSA collects, uses, and transfers the personal information we collect through this Site, as well as through paper copies of membership or grant applications, meeting registration forms, and other forms mailed to us, and through information collected over the phone or via fax or email. Because privacy laws vary from state to state within the United States and from country to country around the world, this Policy may be supplemented or amended by state or country-specific disclosures (“Privacy Notice(s)”), which will be provided to you at the time and on the page where you provide the personal information to which they apply.
As used in this Policy and any Privacy Notice, the term “personal information” means information that identifies you personally, alone or in combination with other information available to us.
Your Consent
By using this Site, or by sending us information via telephone, fax, email, or paper copies (of, for example, membership or grant applications, meeting registration forms, or other forms), you are consenting to the collection, use, and transfer of your personal information as described in this Policy (and any Privacy Notices that apply to you).
If you do not consent to the collection, use and transfer of your personal information as described in this Policy (and any Privacy Notices that apply to you), you may not use this Site .
This Privacy Policy May Change
GSA reserves the right to update or modify this Policy and any Privacy Notice, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version of the Policy or Privacy Notice on this Site. If we modify this Policy or any Privacy Notice, the modifications will only apply to the personal information we collect after we have posted the revised Policy or Privacy Notice on this Site. For your convenience, when we modify this Policy we will post a notice informing users of the change for thirty (30) days on the homepage of this Site.
This Policy was last revised on 10 May 2018 and is effective as of that date.
Why We Collect Personal Information
We collect personal information to help us deliver products and services to our members and interested consumers. Specifically, we need to collect information from you for the following reasons (which is a representative, not an exhaustive, list): (i) so you can register for GSA meetings and events, (ii) so you can subscribe to GSA journals or submit manuscripts for publication, (iii) so you can apply for GSA membership, (iv) so you can submit advertisements for display in GSA publications, (v) so you can apply for internships and mentorship programs and (vi) so you can apply for grants from GSA. Also, your personal information helps us keep you posted on the latest announcements, offers, and events that you might like to hear about.
Your Choices
We respect your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use, and transfer your personal information. This Policy describes some of your choices. In most cases, we will ask you to indicate your choices at the time and on the page where you provide your personal information.
What Information Is Collected and How Is It Used?
When you access and use this Site, or communicate with us via mail, telephone, fax, or email, there are three ways we may collect information about you:
1.	Information You Knowingly and Voluntarily Provide
GSA collects the information you knowingly and voluntarily provide, for example, the information you provide to become a GSA member or register for a GSA meeting or event. Also, you may need to provide information in order to subscribe to a GSA journal or online newsletters, apply for a GSA grant, participate in one of our surveys, request information from GSA, or when you ask us a question or send us feedback. In many cases, this information will include your email address and other personal information. Remember: you may always choose not to provide GSA with personal information. However, if you choose to not provide certain personal information, GSA may not be able to provide you with the product or service you desire.
GSA uses this personal information for the purposes for which you provide it. For example, GSA uses your personal information to complete your membership application and registration process or to confirm your subscription to a GSA journal. If we are permitted to do so under applicable law, we may also use the information we collect for various other business purposes such as customer service, fraud prevention, market research, improving our products and services, and to contact you and your company (if applicable) with information and offers we believe may be of interest to you. In addition, we may remove all the personal information and use the rest for historical, statistical or scientific purposes.
Email Addresses
GSA collects email address information from you when enter your email address on this Site or on applications or other forms. GSA collects email address information from you so that we may confirm and/or deliver your subscription; communicate with you regarding your order or registration; and alert you to other GSA programs and services that may be of interest to you. Oftentimes, our “topical” programs are only advertised through email.
You may “opt out” of receiving these email notices at any time. To opt out of receiving email notices from us, please either update the information in your GSA profile or email . Please provide your name and email address so that we can identify your email address in our database and record your request.
2. Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser
As is true of most websites, GSA gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information typically includes the IP address of your Internet service provider, the name of your operating system, and the name and version of your browser. The information we receive depends on the settings on your web browser. Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings.
This type of information does not identify you personally. Unless you access this Site through an email we have sent you or have created a “user identity” by logging on during one of your visits, this information will not be linked to information that identifies you personally. We use this information to create statistics that help us improve our sites and make them more compatible with the technology used by our Internet visitors.
3. Information Collected By Placing a “Cookie” On Your Computer
GSA may obtain information about you by installing a small text file on your computer's hard drive. This is known as a “cookie.” The GSA server will remember your information/choices during a session. Most cookies expire when you close your browser.
In addition, we use cookies from Google Analytics. The information collected is transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google uses this information on our behalf to evaluate your use of the Site and compiles reports on the activity.
If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. Although you are not required to accept cookies when you visit this Site, you may be unable to use all of the functionality of the site if your browser rejects our cookies.
Sharing and Transferring Personal Information
Unless required to do so by law, we will not provide your personal information to third parties, other than to contractors and partner organizations for the purpose of administering member/customer services on our behalf or with carefully selected business partners. These companies and organizations may use the information we share to provide special opportunities and offers to you related to GSA's mission and goals. These third parties are required by contract to treat your personal information as strictly confidential.
In certain, limited circumstances we may share or transfer personal information to unrelated third parties. For example, we may provide personal information to a third party (i) at your request; (ii) to comply with a legal requirement or court order; (iii) to investigate a possible crime, such as identity theft; or (iv) in connection with the sale, purchase, merger, reorganization, liquidation or dissolution of GSA. If such an event occurs, we will take reasonable steps to protect your personal information.
While it is in our possession, your personal information will generally be stored in GSA databases or databases maintained by our service providers. Most, if not all, of these databases will be stored on servers and storage devices located in the United States. United States data protection laws may not provide as much protection as the data protection laws in force in your country. If you are located in a country outside the United States, by using this Site you consent to the transfer of your personal information to the United States.
Security of Personal Information
Although we maintain reasonable safeguards to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure, misuse or alteration, we cannot guarantee the security of systems that are connected to the Internet nor can we guarantee the security of information transmitted over the Internet. Should a data breach of GSA’s systems occur, GSA will notify you within time frames required by applicable data protection laws.
Children under the Age of Thirteen
We are proud of this Site and we strive to ensure that it does not offend people of any age. However, this Site is not intended for children or minors under the age of thirteen years without the permission of a parent or guardian. If you believe that a child has submitted personal information on or through this Site without the consent and supervision of a parent or guardian, please contact us at gsaservice@geosociety.org or at 3300 Penrose Place, P.O. Box 9140, Boulder, CO 80301 so that we can take appropriate action.
Links to Other Sites
At GSA’s discretion, we may include or offer links to third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies, and GSA has no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. GSA does, however, wish to protect the integrity of our site and we welcome any feedback about these linked sites.
This Policy does not apply to personal information collected on any of these third-party websites. When you access third-party websites through a link on this Site, please take a few minutes to review the privacy policy posted on that site.
Access to Personal Information
If you would like to review, correct and update the personal information you have provided to us, please (a) log in and check the information in your GSA profile; (b) contact GSA Sales and Service at +1-888-443-4472, 303-357-1000 option 3, ; or (c) contact us by postal mail at address below.
If you choose, you may request to delete your account with us (be forgotten). You must contact GSA in writing at 3300 Penrose Place, Boulder, Colorado, 80301.
Retention of Personal Information
GSA retains the personal information collected as long as necessary to provide the services, products and information you request or as permitted by applicable law. Some data, such a as that gathered by Google Analytics, is purged at regular intervals.
Governing Law
GSA is a United States not-for-profit, tax-exempt (501C3) corporation. This Agreement shall be governed under the laws of the State of New York, United States of America without regard to its conflicts of law provisions.
Questions about this Policy or our Data Practices
If you have questions or concerns about this Policy or any Privacy Notice, please contact at:
